Guide to the Joseph L. Fisher papers, 1962-1991
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Joseph L. Fisher papers
1962-1991
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Joseph L. Fisher
C0028
64 linear feet (79 boxes)
This collection relates to Fisher's career as an economist, educator, and U.S. Congressman. The materials include lectures and comments on conservation and natural resources, scrapbooks, pamphlets, appointment books, and correspondence. Materials that relate to his political career in U.S. House of Representatives include correspondence, speeches, press releases, reports, newsclippings, issue papers, testimony, statements, questionnaires, background publications, guidelines, charts, and legislation.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Margaret Fisher in 1992-1995.
Biographical Information
Joseph Lyman Fisher (1914-1992), economist, educator, author, and congressman, was born in Salesville, Rhode Island on January 11, 1914. After earning his undergraduate degree at Bowdoin College, Fisher went on to graduate work at the London School of Economics, Harvard University, and George Washington University. In 1942 he married the former Margaret Saunders Winslow. Fisher's career, spanning over fifty years, included planner for the National Resources Planning Board, economist for the United States Department of State, executive officer and economist for the Council of Economic Advisors, president of Resources for the Future, a member of the United States House of Representatives (1974-1981), Virginia Secretary of Human Resources, special assistant to the president of George Mason University, and president of the National Academy of Public Administration. In addition, Fisher was deeply involved in community activities, having been chairman of the Arlington County Board, chairman of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA), president and chairman of the Washington Metropolitan Council of Governments (COG), and moderator and chairman of the board of the Unitarian Universalist Association. He also wrote several books, including World Prospects for Natural Resources (1964) and Resources in America's Future (1963).
Scope and Content
This collection is divided into two series. Series 1 relates to Fisher's career as an economist, educator, and U.S. Congressman. The materials cover the years 1962-1991 and include lectures and comments on conservation and natural resources, scrapbooks, pamphlets, appointment books, and correspondence.
Series 2 of the collection relates to Fisher's political career in U.S. House of Representatives (1974-1981). The materials cover the years 1974-1981 and include correspondence, speeches, press releases, reports, newsclippings, issue papers, testimony, statements, questionnaires, background publications, guidelines, charts, and legislation.
Arrangement
Organized into two series.
Series 1: Academic Career/Government Appointments, 1962-1991
Series 2: U.S. House of Representatives, 1974-1981
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the papers of other local and national politicians from Northern Virginia.
Index Terms
Persons:
Fisher, Joseph Lyman, 1914-1992.
Corporate Names:
George Mason University.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Ways and Means.
Geographical Names:
Arlington County (Va.)
Subjects:
Conservation of natural resources--Law and legislation--United States.; Energy policy--Law and legislation--United States.; Taxation--Law and legislation--United States.
Contents List
- Series 1: Academic Career/Government Appointments, 1962-1991
  Papers relate to Fisher's career as an economist, educator, and U.S. Congressman. The materials cover the years 1962-1991 and include: lectures and comments on conservation and natural resources, scrapbooks, pamphlets, appointment books, and correspondence.
  - MISC. NOTES (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - BROOKINGS CONFERENCE NOTES (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AMERICAN PULPWOOD "SMALL WOODLAND OWNERS" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SOIL CONSERVATION SOCIETY OF AMERICA NOTES (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NEW ENGLANDER ARTICLE (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NAS - NRC COMMENTS (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - WISCONSIN GOV CONF.. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ICMA PA MEETING (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - SEATTLE - PARKS (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - BRANDYWINE V ASSN. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - LAND GRANT COLLEGES (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AIR CONSERVATION ASSN. AAAS 12/62 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - LEHIGH UNIV BETHLEHEM JULY 23, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - GENEVA UN CONF. FEB 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - PROFILE ARTICLE (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - U OF MASS SEMINAR APRIL, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - SOIL CONSERVATION SOCIETY MARCH, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - RESOURCES FOR THE FUTURE (NATURAL RESOURCE PROBLEMS AND THE FUTURE OF THE AMERICAN ECONOMY (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - RFF PROGRAM LETTERS ETC (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - JLF BIBLIOGRAPHY 1956 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - WHITE HOUSE CONFERENCE ON INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - REPORT OF THE TASK FORCE ON RESOURCES AND ENVIRONMENT DECEMBER 5, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ISSUES (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1963 - '64 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1963 - '64 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1965 - '67 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ARLINGTON COUNTY 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SPEECHES CO BD (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - SPEECHES CO BD (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - FISHER CONGRESSIONAL CAMPAIGN - CONTENTS AND INDEX (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - NEWS CLIPPINGS 1973 - 74 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ANNOUNCEMENT OF CANDIDACY 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - FISHER PRE - PRIMARY: 1972 - FEB 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - TELEPHONING (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - FISHER - PRIMARY CAMPAIGN: MARCH - JUNE 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - FISHER - PRIMARY ELECTION JUNE 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SPEECHES - 1974 CAMPAIGN (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SPEECHES, TESTIMONY: 1973 - 4 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ISSUES SHEETS: 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PRESS RELEASES - PRE - PRIMARY: 1973 - 74 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PRESS PRE - PRIMARY (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CANDIDACY - OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - PRESS - RELEASES: 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - PRESS RELEASES - GENERAL ELECTION 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - FINANCIAL REPORT: 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - CAMPAIGN CORRESPONDENCE (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - CAMPAIGN PHOTOS (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - MAIL OUTS TO VOTERS (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - BROYHILL, JOEL T 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - BROYHILL, JOEL T 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - BROYHILL, JOEL T 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - BROYHILL, JOEL T 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - BROYHILL, JOEL T 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - BROYHILL ON ECONOMICS (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - MEDIA - PRESS RELEASES (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ELECTION DAY AND ANALYSIS CLIPS: NOV 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - CERTIFICATION OF ELECTION 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - RESIGNATION FROM CO BD DEC 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - LETTERHEAD (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - ANNOUNCEMENT SPEECHES (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1976 ISSUES (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - CAMPAIGN '76 - PRINTED MATERIALS (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - CAMPAIGN SPEECHES AND NOTES 1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - ENDORSEMENTS - PRINTING: 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - PRESS RELEASES AND MAILINGS: 1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - CLIPS: 1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - CLIP - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - FINANCIAL REPORTS - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - CAMPAIGN '76 - OPPOSITIONS (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - KEY PERSONS 1976 CAMPAIGN (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - VINCE CALLAHAN (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - CAMPAIGN MEETINGS (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - CORRESPONDENCE - MISCELLANEOUS (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - ELECTION RESULTS: 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - SPEECHES - CAMPAIGN 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - CLIPS AND RELEASES: 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - FINANCE - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ELECTION RESULTS: 1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - VOTE RATINGS: 1977 - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - VOTES RATINGS: 1977 - 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - VOTE RATINGS - 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - CLIPS - OUR RELEASES (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - CAMPAIGN CLIPS (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - CAMPAIGN CLIPS (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - CLIPS: 1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - SPEECHES - 1980 CAMPAIGN (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - MISC CAMPAIGN MATERIALS (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - PRESS RELEASES AND LETTERS (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - POST ELECTION MATERIAL 1980 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - JLF NEWSLETTER (COMPLETE FILE 1975 - 80) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - CAMPAIGN 1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - CAMPAIGN 1982 - SUPPORTERS (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - CAMPAIGN 1982 - SUPPORTERS (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CAMPAIGN 1982 - SUPPORTS (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - ORGANIZATION 1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - CAMPAIGN FOR SENATE 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - APPOINTMENTS 1977 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - APPOINTMENTS 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - APPOINTMENTS 1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - APPOINTMENTS 1978 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - APPOINTMENTS 1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - APPOINTMENTS 1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - LECTURES (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS, PUBLIC APPEARANCES, FEB TO MARCH 1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS AND APPOINTMENTS, JULY 1976 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS, APPOINTMENTS - JULY, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - PUBLIC APPEARANCES APPOINTMENTS 1976 - 77 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - PUBLIC APPEARANCE 1978 - 79 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - PUBLIC APPEARANCE 1978 - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SPEECHES PUBLIC APPEARANCES 1979 - 1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - SPEECHES (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - SPEECHES 1972 - 1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - SPEECHES 1974 - 1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - SPEECHES 1978 - 1979 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - SPEECHES 1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - SPEECHES 1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - SPEECHES 1981 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - CAPITOL PHOTOS (FISHER OUTSIDE CAPITOL BUILDING) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - MUG SHOTS (FISHER PORTRAITS) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - PHOTOS - MISCELLANEOUS, PT. I 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - PHOTOS - MISCELLANEOUS PT. II 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - PHOTOS 1976-1980 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - NEGATIVES (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - CAMPAIGN CONTRIBUTORS (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - ISSUE AREAS - ABORTION (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - ISSUE AREAS - AMNESTY (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - ISSUE AREAS - CAMPAIGN REFORM (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - ISSUE AREAS - CIVIL SERVICE (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - ISSUE AREAS - CONSTITUENT SERVICE (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - ISSUE AREAS - CRIMINAL JUSTICE (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - ISSUE AREAS - CULTURE (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - ISSUE AREAS - DEFENCE (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - ISSUE AREAS - DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - ISSUE AREAS - EDUCATION ELEMENTARY AND SECONDARY (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - ISSUE AREAS - EDUCATION, HIGHER (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - ISSUE AREAS - EMPLOYMENT AND MANPOWER (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - ISSUE AREAS - ENERGY (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - ISSUE AREAS - THE ENVIRONMENT (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - ISSUE AREAS - FOOD AND AGRICULTURE (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - ISSUE AREAS - FOREIGN POLICY (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - ISSUE AREAS - GENERAL (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - ISSUE AREAS - GOVT REFORM (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - GUN CONTROL ISSUE AREA (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - ISSUE AREAS - HATCH ACT (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - ISSUE AREAS - HEALTH (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - ISSUE AREAS - HOUSING (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - ISSUE AREAS - IMPEACHMENT (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - ISSUES - INFLATION (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - ISSUE AREAS - LAND USE (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - MORAL MAJORITY (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - PRODUCTIVITY (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - ISSUE AREAS - REGIONAL ISSUES (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - ISSUES AREAS R + D (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - ISSUE AREAS - SENIOR CITIZENS (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - SOCIAL SECURITY - FEDERAL EMPLOYEES (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - ISSUE AREAS - TRANSPORTATION (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - ISSUE AREAS - VETERANS (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - ISSUE PAPERS (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - ISSUE PAPERS (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - ISSUE PAPERS (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - ISSUE PAPERS (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - SECRETARY OF HUMAN RESOURCES (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - SECRETARY OF HUMAN RESOURCES 1982 - 84 NEWS CLIPPINGS (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - STATE OF STATE'S ECONOMY (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - VIRGINIA'S INVESTMENT IN JOB TRAINING: A PROPOSAL FOR GOVERNOR'S ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - CHANGING HEALTH CARE COST (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - PREVENTION IN HUMAN RESOURCES (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - HUMAN RESOURCES AGENCIES IN VIRGINIA (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - SPEECHES ON HUMAN RESOURCES (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - NEW DIRECTIONS FOR HUMAN RESOURCES (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - CORRESPONDENCE (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - MIGRANT FARM WORKERS ON VIRGINIA'S EASTERN SHORE (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - BALILES (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - AGING PROGRAM (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - AMERICAN CULTURE SEMINAR (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - AMERICAN FORESTRY ASSOCIATION (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - GMU CAMPUS DEVELOPMENT TEAM (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - CAUNOX, PETER J (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - CENTER FOR CONFLICT ANALYSIS AND RESOLUTION (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - CONFLICT RESOLUTION COURSE JOHN BURTON MATERIAL (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - DION, JEFFREY (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - DISSERTATION COMMITTEES (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - GENERAL ASSEMBLY (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - GEORGE MASON INSTITUTE (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - GMU (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - GMU PRESS (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - GOV AND LEG RELATIONS PROPOSAL (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - CENTER FOR HEALTH POLICY (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - HUMAN SERVICES CONFERENCE (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - HUMAN SERVICES I & R COUNCIL (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - INTERNATIONAL HOSPICE INSTITUTE (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - GMU INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - INTERNATIONALIZING THE CURRICULUM AT GMU: A PRELIMINARY REPORT (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - JOB DESCRIPTIONS 1987 - 1988 (ADMIN.. AND COORDINATORS) (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - JOHNSON, PRESIDENT (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - LAMBDA ALPHA INTERNATIONAL (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - LOCAL GOVERNMENT FORUM (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - MASON DEMOCRATIC CLUB (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - N VA CHAIR IN LOCAL GOVT (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - N V INSTITUTE (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - N VA MEDIATION SERVICE (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - THE POLITICS OF ECONOMICS AND VICE VERSA (OR HOW ECONOMISTS AND POLITICIANS FRUSTRATE EACH OTHER) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - REPORT ON THE FEASIBILITY STUDY FOR A PRINCE WILLIAM CENTRE FOR HIGHER EDUCATION (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - A PROPOSAL FOR A UNIVERSITY PRESENCE IN PRINCE WILLIAM COUNTY (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - PUBLIC AFFAIRS DEPARTMENT (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - PUBLIC CHOICE CENTER (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - PUBLIC POLICY PROGRAM SEARCH ACTIVITIES (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - INSTITUTE OF PUBLIC POLICY (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - INSTITUTE OF PUBLIC POLICY (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - INSTITUTE OF PUBLIC POLICY (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - INSTITUTE OF PUBLIC POLICY (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - CENTER FOR STUDY OF RACE AND ETHNIC RELATIONS (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - REORGANIZATION - UNIVERSITY COMMISSION OF 1983 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - SCHEIBER (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - SOUTHPORT INSTITUTE (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - SOUTHPORT INSTITUTE (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - VA ALLIANCE FOR THE PUBLIC SERVICE (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - OUTLINES READING LISTS, ETC FOR POLICY COURSES (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - GOV 401 PUBLIC POLICY PROCESS SPRING 1991 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - GOV 463 - LOBBYING AND PUBLIC POLICY (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - GMU COURSE 1981 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - HUMAN RESOURCES POLICY SEMINAR (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - HONOR SEMINAR GOVT 490 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - GOVT 490 HUMAN AND NATURAL RESOURCES POLICY (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - GOVT 490 SEMINAR HUMAN AND NATURAL RESOURCES POLICY (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - PUAD 463 LOBBYING SPRING 1991 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - FISHER PUAD 640 SPRING 86 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - POLICY COURSE - SPRING '86 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - PUAD 640 FALL 1986 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - PUAD PUBLIC POLICY PROCESS SPRING 1987 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - NEWS CLIPPINGS (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - PUBLIC POLICY PROCESS PUAD 640 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - PUAD 640 FALL '88 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - PUAD 640 SPRING 1989 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - PUAD 640 FALL 1989 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - PUAD 640 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - PUAD 640 FALL 1990 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - PUAD 640 FALL 1990 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - PUAD 749 ISSUES IN PUBLIC POLICY SPRING 1990 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - PUAD 749 ISSUES IN PUBLIC POLICY SPRING 1990 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - ANOTHER LOOK AT THE METRO CAMPUS AND THE ARLINGTON COMMUNITY 1983 - 87 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - ARLINGTON /GMU COMMITTEE (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - ARLINGTON /GMU COMMITTEE (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - ARLINGTON /GMU COMMITTEE (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU COMMITTEE (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU COMMITTEE (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU COMMITTEE (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU PROJECT (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU DEVELOPMENT COMMITTEE (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU DEVELOPMENT COMMITTEE (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU FINANCE SUBCOM (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU REPORT (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU REPORT (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU REPORT (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - ARLINGTON / GMU PROGRAM PLANNING COMMITTEE (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - THE NEW GMU - ARLINGTON CAMPUS: A PROGRAM FOR AN EDUCATING COMMITTEE (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - NEWS CLIPPINGS (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - ARLINGTON - GMU (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - FRIENDS OF GMU / ARLINGTON CAMPUS (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - VCU SEMINAR, FALL 1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - VCU CLASS / PAD 691 SPRING '85 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - 1984 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - DIRECTIONS FOR AMERICA (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - DIRECTIONS FOR AMERICA (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - ABORTION MATERIAL 1980 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - AIRPORTS 1981 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - ASSESSMENT (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - BACKGROUND MATERIAL - 1980 DEBATES, SPEECHES, ISSUES PAPERS (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - BEYER FOR LT.. GOV 1989 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - BILLS COSPONSORED (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - BOWDON COLLEGE (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - BUDGET (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - CAMPAIGN CONTRIBUTIONS (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - CAMPAIGN 1983 - 84 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - CARDS TO JLF (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - CBF LAUDS COM (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - CHESAPEAKE BAY FOUNDATION (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - CHESAPEAKE FUTURE PROJECT (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - CHINA TRIP 1979 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - CLAREMONT SCHOOL OF THEOLOGY (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - COAL (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - COMMITTEE FOR NATIONAL SECURITY (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - COMMON CAUSE (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - CONFERENCES (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - CONGRESS (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - FINANCES - REPORTING AND DISCLOSURE 1974 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - CONGRESSIONAL FINANCIAL DISCLOSURE 1975 - 80 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - CONGRESSIONAL PAPERS (GMU LIBRARY) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - CONSERVATION FOUNDATION (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - CORRESPONDENCE (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - CORRESPONDENCE - POLITICAL (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - DEMOCRAT COMMITTEE - ARLINGTON 1974 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - DEMOCRATIC STUDY GROUP (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - DUKE PAPER (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - EDUCATION / AGING PAPER (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - EMERSON (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - ENERGY AND ENVIRONMENT (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - ENVIRONMENT (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - ENVIRONMENTAL AND ENERGY STUDY INSTITUTE (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - ENVIRONMENTAL STUDY CONFERENCE (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - ENVIRONMENTAL STUDY CONFERENCE (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - FAIRFAX CULTURAL TASK FORCE (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - FINANCES - BUDGET 1974 - 1980 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - JLF POLITICAL (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - FORMER MEMBERS OF CONGRESS (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - FOUNDATIONS (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - FRANKING COMMISSION (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - PROPOSED CHANGES TO THE HATCH ACT (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - HOUSE DEMOCRATS - 93RD CONGRESS (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - INCOME SECURITY (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - CIT (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - IHI (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - INSTITUTE OF ENERGY ANALYSIS (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - LECHNER, IRA 1981 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - LOUDOUN (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - MILLER CAMPAIGN 1978 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - MILLIKEN CAMPAIGN 1986 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - MISCELLANEOUS 1980 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - MISCELLANEOUS INTEMS: JLF ARTICLES AND NOTES (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - MITRE LECTURE 11/10/81 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - MITRE LECTURE 11/10/81 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - MITRE LECTURE 11/10/81 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - NAPA BEYOND DISTRUST: BUILDING BRIDGES BETWEEN CONGRESS AND THE EXECUTIVE (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - NAPA CONGRESS AND THE EXECUTIVE: IMPROVING THE MANAGEMENT AND IMPLEMENTATION OF PUBLIC POLICY 1990 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - NAPA - PRESIDENTIAL SEARCH COM (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - NATIONAL ACADEMY OF PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - NATIONAL ECONOMIST CLUB JLF (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - VIRGINIA COMMUNITY FOUNDATION (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - PAPERS (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - PAPERS (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - PLANNED COMMUNITY ARCHIVES (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - POLITICAL ACTION ORGANIZATION (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - POLITICAL CAMPAIGNS 1991 (VAN HUYCK AND MILLER) (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - POLLING (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - POP REF BUR (PRB) (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - QUESTIONNAIREs, RATINGS (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - QUOTATIONS, MISC (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - REGULATION (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - REPORT ON WOOD STOVES, ENVIRONMENTAL CONSEQUENCES (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - RESOURCES FOR THE FUTURE (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - RESUMES (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - ROBB CAMPAIGN - 1981 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - ROBB BOOK (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - ROBB BOOK (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - ROBB BOOK (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - ROBB LECTURES (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - ROBB LECTURES (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - SENATE CAMPAIGN 1990 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - SPEECHES I OF II (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - SPEECHES II TO II (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - STATEWIDE HUMAN SERVICES INFO AND REFERRAL ADVISORY COUNCIL - VA (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - TENNIS PARTNERS (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - VA ENVIRONMENTAL LAW JOURNAL (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - WEINBERG CAMPAIGN (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - PAUL SIMON CAMPAIGN (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - THE WILDERNESS SOCIETY (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - WILDERNESS SOCIETY (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - WILDERNESS SOCIETY (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - FRANK WOLF (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - WOLF (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - WORLD FUTURE SOCIETY (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - WORLD RESOURCES INSTITUTE (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - CHURCH PROGRAMS (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - FISHER SERMONS I (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - FISHER SERMONS II (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - TALKS PLUS DRAFTS OF SERMONS (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - JLF PERSONAL AERONAUTICS AND SPACE ENGINEERING BOARD (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - JLF PERSONAL AMERICAN FORESTRY ASSOCIATION (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - JLF PERSONAL ASPEN INSTITUTE (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - JLF PERSONAL BOWDOIN COLLEGE (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - JLF PERSONAL COMMISSION ON INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - JLF PERSONAL COMMISSION ON NATURAL RESOURCES (NATIONAL RESEARCH COUNCIL) (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - JLF PERSONAL COMMITTEE ON DULLES AND NATIONAL (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - JLF PERSONAL AND FORMER MEMBERS OF CONGRESS (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - JLF PERSONAL MISCELLANEOUS BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - JLF PERSONAL MISCELLANEOUS SOCIAL CORRESPONDENCE (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - JLF PERSONAL COSMOS CLUB (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - JLF PERSONAL ELECTRICAL POWER RESEARCH INSTITUTE (EPRI) (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - INSTITUTE FOR ENERGY ANALYSIS (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - J L FISHER LETTERHEAD (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - PEGGY FISHER (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - JLF PERSONAL GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - JLF PERSONAL GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - JLF PERSONAL GOVERNMENT AFFAIRS INSTITUTE -OPM (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - JLF PERSONAL GREATER WASHINGTON RESEARCH CENTRE (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - JLF PERSONAL GREATER WASHINGTON RESEARCH CENTRE (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - JLF PERSONAL HELP THE AGED (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - JLF PERSONAL HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES (Box 39, Folder 2)